Guide to the George B. and Richard K. Culver Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
George B. and Richard K. Culver papers
1887-1905
SC0260
Culver, George Bliss, 1875-1949.
Culver, Richard Keith, 1873-1939
1 Linear feet
Collection consists of class notebooks, with some additional papers including letters, clippings, and sketches, and one scrapbook on Lake George, New York. George B. Culver's notebooks, 1895-96 and undated, are from Stanford classes in education, chemistry, English, and the psychology of childhood, with one notebook from a physiology class prior to his attendance at Stanford, 1887. Notebooks by Richard K. Culver, 1892-1895, are from Stanford classes in American literature, English literature, ethics, geology, hygiene, paleontology (Prof. James P. Smith), German composition, and physics; many of his notebooks include sketches. Other papers of Richard K. Culver include pen and ink drawings, two letters, and clippings of his political cartoons, 1896-1905.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
George B. Culver earned his A.B. in zoology at Stanford University in 1897. He later served as Dean of Men at Stanford, 1920-1938. His brother Richard K. Culver earned his A.B. in bionomics at Stanford in 1899. He was a nationally syndicated cartoonist before becoming a citrus grower in 1931.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of class notebooks, with some additional papers including letters, clippings, and sketches, and one scrapbook on Lake George, New York. George B. Culver's notebooks, 1895-96 and undated, are from Stanford classes in education, chemistry, English, and the psychology of childhood, with one notebook from a physiology class prior to his attendance at Stanford, 1887. Notebooks by Richard K. Culver, 1892-1895, are from Stanford classes in American literature, English literature, ethics, geology, hygiene, paleontology (Prof. James P. Smith), German composition, and physics; many of his notebooks include sketches. Other papers of Richard K. Culver include pen and ink drawings, two letters, and clippings of his political cartoons, 1896-1905.
Access Terms
Culver, George Bliss, 1875-1949.; Culver, Richard Keith, 1873-1939; Smith, James Perrin, 1864-1931.; George, Lake.; Notebooks.; Political cartoons.; Scrapbooks
Collection Contents
- George B. Culver
  - Notebook from physiology class, 1887 (Box 1)
  - Notebook from psychology of childhood class, S.U. (Box 1)
  - Notebook from education class, S.U., 1896 (Box 1)
  - Notebook, Chemistry class, no date (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, English class, no date (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Richard K. Culver
  - Notebooks from Stanford classes in American literature, English literature, ethics, geology, hygiene, and paleontology (Prof. James P. Smith), 1893-95 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, ethics class, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, geology(includes many sketches), 1894 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, German composition, no date (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, physics, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Original pen and ink sketches (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers (letters, clippings, farewell dinner program) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper cartoons 1896-1905 (photocopies) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper cartoons (originals), 1896-1905 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Scrapbook on Lake George (Box 1)